<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shannon Young</title>
    <link>https://slyoung1222.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Shannon Young</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 12:14:34 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://slyoung1222.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bringing the Garden Inside - February 2021</title>
      <link>https://slyoung1222.github.io/post/post-february-npa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slyoung1222.github.io/post/post-february-npa/</guid>
      <description>The joys and surprises of the February garden—many of us started the month singing the praises of newly bloomed Helleborus only to find ourselves buried in snowdrifts mid-month. By month’s end, a series of sunny days quickly melted the snow and brought us to a moment garden designer Dan Pearson (2021) describes as “a notable shift from slumber. Bright rosettes amongst the leaf litter, looking determined and suddenly visible. Newly green amongst the darkness of foliage from last year, which is daily being pulled to earth by the earthworms and mouldering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing the Garden Inside - January 2021</title>
      <link>https://slyoung1222.github.io/post/post-january-npa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slyoung1222.github.io/post/post-january-npa/</guid>
      <description>I once read a gardener’s advice to always keep a cutting from the garden inside the house, preferably on display in a high traffic area with lots of visibility. The opportunity to see our plants closely and in the comfort of home offers new impressions such as textural nuance, color depth, or the beauty of a silhouette. I filed this wisdom away for a time when my gardening idea box was not quite so overflowing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing the Garden Inside--April 2021</title>
      <link>https://slyoung1222.github.io/post/post-april-npa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slyoung1222.github.io/post/post-april-npa/</guid>
      <description>In April, I pondered the concept of memorial gardens, specifically how we memorialize a loved one in our gardens. Since my grandmother who raised me died in January, I’ve considered the ways she led me to gardening and how I might outwardly remember her in mine. My garden always provides a salve in challenging times, and certainly did so during the loss of someone dear to me. In her celebrated book, The Well-Gardened Mind: The Restorative Power of Nature, psychologist and gardener Sue Stuart-Smith (2020) notes, “Our deep existential need for symbolic survival is one of the reasons why when people are confronted with death, their relationship with nature often takes on a whole new significance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing the Garden Inside--March 2021</title>
      <link>https://slyoung1222.github.io/post/post-march-npa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slyoung1222.github.io/post/post-march-npa/</guid>
      <description>In March, I delved into a study of color by collecting monochromatic arrangements. As my young garden begins its fourth growing season, I’ve shifted my attention from establishing structure, boundaries, and permanent plantings to the finer details of color, texture, and ephemeral accents in the garden. Blooms and color were once an incidental or frivolous luxury in my garden work. Now they are the joyful reward of my earlier labor. Planning a succession of color has occupied my thoughts and brightened my days this winter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shannon Young</title>
      <link>https://slyoung1222.github.io/author/shannon-young/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://slyoung1222.github.io/author/shannon-young/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
